M. Murat Ardag



Cypriot (EU), British Overseas & Turkish



ABOUT

I am a data scientist specializing in psychometrics, psycholinguistics, and modeling subjectivity. My passion is revealing and understanding heterogeneity. That translates into various unsupervised machine learning and natural language processing applications like latent profile analysis, latent class analysis, psychological profiles with psychometric networks, semantic networks, concept class analysis.

SKILLS

Data Science

2+ years **?**: pandas, numpy, scikit-learn, matplotlib, seaborn

7+ years **Q**: tidyverse, tidymodels, tidyflow, easystats, lavaan (& its ecosystem), psychometric networks (collection of packages), quanteda (& its ecosystem), spacy

Since 2021 Tensorflow-Keras, pytorch, prophet

Programming

Since 2021 Git. Bash

Databases

Since 2021 Postgres, SQLite, MongoDB

Deployment

Since 2021 AWS (EC2, RDS), Docker, Flask

Machine Learning

Regression, classification, time series, natural language processing

EDUCATION

2021	Data Science Bootcamp
	Spiced Academy, Berlin, Germany
2015 - 2018	Ph.D. in Political Science
	CvO Universität Oldenburg,
	Oldenburg, Germany
2008 - 2012	M.A. in Political Science
	Bilkent University, Ankara, Turkey
2005 - 2008	M.A. in International Relations
	Galatasaray University, Istanbul,
	Turkey

SELECTED PROJECTS

Measuring Organizational Practices

Natural language processing

Movie Recommender

Unsupervised machine learning

Image Classification with Deep Learning

Deep learning

Dockerized Data Pipeline

Involves: MongoDB, ETL job (sentiment analysis), Postgres & Slackbot

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

02-11/2020

Postdoctoral Fellow

Jacobs University, Bremen, Germany

- Worked as the lead data analyst in a third-party funded project (Business Finland & Hofstede Insights)
- > Developed a dictionary that measures organizational culture with Hofstede's Multi-Focus Model
- Used the R tidy ecosystem; the quanteda ecosystem (including spacyr), rJST, tidytext, sentimentr & the easystats ecosystem

Since 02/2019

Affiliated Postdoctoral Fellow

Bremen International School of Social Sciences, Bremen, Germany

Conducting research, publishing academic papers, teaching methods classes

01/2019 - 02/2020

(Interim-) Academic Coordinator

CvO Universität Oldenburg,

Oldenburg, Germany

- Developed/updated the research methods curriculum by adding new quantitative & qualitative techniques and inviting experts to teach them
- Taught quantitative methods classes and academic writing
- Coordinated everything academic (receiving, entering grades, preparing diplomas) in a consortium composed of four European and three African universities

07/2012 - 07/2018

Research Assistant Lecturer

CvO Universität Oldenburg,

Oldenburg, Germany

- Taught seminars on political psychology, national identity, populism, prejudice, and academic writing
- > Conducted research; published academic papers

LANGUAGES

Turkish (Native), English (Proficient), German (Intermediate)